<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <title>Your Title - governance</title>
 <link href="https://example.com/tag/governance/index.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="https://example.com/tag/governance.html"/>
 <updated>2016-12-05T13:31:33+00:00</updated>
 <id>https://example.com/tag/governance.html</id>
 <author>
   <name>Author Here</name>
 </author>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Labour bigwigs still trying to defend the Digital Economy Act</title>
   <link href="https://example.com/labour-bigwigs-still-trying-to-defend-the-digital-economy-act/"/>
   <updated>2012-02-25T22:10:02+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://example.com/labour-bigwigs-still-trying-to-defend-the-digital-economy-act</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Harriet bloody Harman made me write to my MP, Jim Fizpatrick, today. FWIW.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dear Mr Fitzpatrick,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Given your comfortable majority I doubt you’ll be too worried at the loss of one vote, but can I briefly give you my reasons why I, as a lifelong Labour voter, could not vote for you at the last election and will not be able to do so next time either?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I was never too worried about civil liberties until a few years ago. I’d actually be happy if there was a national identity card, for instance. I don’t think I’m a paranoid libertarian nutter (fingers crossed). But I was dismayed by a number of measures introduced by the last Labour government starting in the climate of fear whipped up after the major terrorist incidents of 2001 and 2005.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Successive Labour Home Secretaries seemed to want to prove themselves more macho than their predecessor, and more tough on crime (rather than its causes) than the Opposition. Police were given more powers and used them to kettle protestors and prevent photography in public places. The UK acquiesced in the torture and long-term imprisonment without trial of British citizens. All this was not something that affected me personally so I noted it without allowing it to change my long-term loyalty to the party.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But then in the dying days of the government the Digital Economy Bill was introduced and passed without adequate debate. If there had been time to organize a coherent opposition to it then it would probably have suffered the same fate as the US SOPA and PIPA bills. But despite the help of people like Tom Watson, it was not possible to raise public awareness of the consequences of passing this bill until too late. It became the Digital Economy Act, the party lost the election (for unrelated reasons sadly) and we were stuck with it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By contrast with the policing and security measures, the Act deals with something I know a little about: technology and the internet. I am a former technology director of an investment bank and am now the Chief Technology Officer of a financial services startup company.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My company’s success depends on being able to respond in an agile way to the changing business environment. We can do this much faster than large corporates, however much they spend on R&amp;amp;D. We can certainly do this much faster than regulators and legislators, no matter much lobbyists spend on influencing them. But we are left standing by the bad guys, who can innovate before a legislator has even heard of the problem.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My contention is this:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;It's not possible to anticipate everything the bad guys might do, so you can't legislate for their future exploits.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you write over-broad legislation to counter this problem then you stifle legitimate business and prevent beneficial innovation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you give broad powers to law enforcement agencies they will use them for purposes for which they were not originally intended. Sad but true.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The law already makes crime criminal. More law will not actually change this.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The central problem is a failure of established businesses to give the customer what they want nowadays.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The last point is key. Perhaps I could include some comparisons between the user’s experience of piracy compared to a legitimate purchase:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/GxzeV.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/steal_this_comic.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;498&quot; height=&quot;469&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Just to reiterate, I’m not supporting piracy. I’m saying if the content owners gave customers what they wanted, made it as easy as pirating it, and didn’t try to retain an inappropriate level of control over what the customer did with the content then they might still have a business model.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I could go on; I’m quite angry about this. The Digital Economy Act will have no effect on piracy (or child pornography or anything else it’s supposed to fix). I can think of ten ways of defeating its measures, so the bad guys can doubtless think of 100. Harriet Harman (and by implication your party) appears still to think otherwise: &lt;a href=&quot;https://j.mp/zyvlFC&quot;&gt;https://j.mp/zyvlFC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Digital Economy Act reinforces the principal of a censored internet and adds disconnection for suspected infringers. What legislators should actually be doing is ensuring a free internet with access provided on a the same basis as other utilities.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’d vote for a party that supported that.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Regards,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dominic Sayers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Is the board meeting past its prime?</title>
   <link href="https://example.com/is-the-board-meeting-past-its-prime/"/>
   <updated>2012-01-12T20:44:32+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://example.com/is-the-board-meeting-past-its-prime</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In December the New York Times ran a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2011/12/18/fashion/social-media-reduce-allure-of-high-school-reunions.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;story&lt;/a&gt; that asked “is the high school reunion past its prime?” The thesis was that Facebook and similar services had made such infrequent meetings redundant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“Even as a borderline user of social networking, I have a pretty good grasp of where people are, what they do, their family life, etc.,” he said. “So a lot of the mystery of the traditional reunion was missing.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;said one interviewee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This chimed with what I’ve been thinking about board meetings since reading Steve Blank’s posts on the subject bank in June. He’s specifically talking about managing startups, but much of what he says applies equally to any company that has an active board. In particular, it’s worth reading the whole of &lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2011/06/01/why-board-meetings-suck-%E2%80%93-part-1-of-2/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Why Board Meetings Suck&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;Startup board meetings occur every 4-6 weeks. While that’s great when you showed up in your horse and buggy, the strategy-to-tactic-to implementation lag is painful at Internet speeds.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And again,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;For the founders, “the get ready for the board meeting” drill is often a performance rather than a snapshot. Powerpoints, spreadsheets and rehearsals consume time for materials that are used once and discarded.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, a very good question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;In the age of the Internet why do we need to get together in one room on a fixed schedule? Why do we need to wait a month to six weeks to see progress?&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why indeed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The traditional board cycle as practised, well, everywhere is a 20th century construct constrained by what was possible when joint-stock companies were first invented. What has technology done for the board meeting in the last 100 years?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Spreadsheets have replaced ledgers&lt;/strong&gt;. This has revolutionized the production of reports, which previously would have been done by a laborious series of manual calculations.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duplication&lt;/strong&gt; has gone from quill pen to carbon copies to photocopies to laser printed documents. Some boards now get their board packs on an iPad.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communications technology&lt;/strong&gt; has allowed people to dial in or even appear on a video link.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is all impressive but how has it changed the board &lt;em&gt;process&lt;/em&gt;? The answer is not at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clue to how to do this is in the New York Times story at the top. People put less value on infrequent meetings because they are in constant touch with each other. When stuff happens they know about it immediately - the reunion has less value as a catch-up exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The board can do this already, and good boards do. As &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.guykawasaki.com/2006/03/the_art_of_the_.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;many people have said&lt;/a&gt;, there shouldn’t be any surprises at a board meeting. Controversial topics need to be aired in advance. The CEO shouldn’t expect to sell a brand new concept at the meeting itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;Nothing MAJOR is ever decided at the board meeting&quot; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bothsidesofthetable.com/2010/02/12/running-more-effective-board-meetings-at-startups/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mark Suster&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is, we can make this &lt;em&gt;easier&lt;/em&gt;. It’s already good practise; we can make it widespread. It shouldn’t depend on the people-management skills of the CEO, it should be built into the workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not even hard to do. We know how to get things done with Google Docs, Quora, Twitter, WordPress and Plaxo (or their many equivalents). Translate that knowledge to a secure, cloud-based service and there is the beginning of your asynchronous, social boardroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Straight away you can avoid the latency inherent in building a board pack. Board members can begin the discussion as soon as information is available. Conversation can proceed when people are free to pursue it, even in multiple time zones. The mere fact of storing one month’s report with its siblings from prior months ought to encourage some consistency in reporting. A permanent, searchable record of the conversation around a particular subject ought to discourage unproductive circular discussions and allow a corporate memory to evolve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also a good basis for automating the production of many of the reports. Once automated,  consistency is built-in, as is freedom from human error. Trending and management by exception become possible. The focus of the board’s activities would be the company dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But people still have meetups, even people who live their lives online. Check out the activity on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Meetup&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://lanyrd.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lanyrd&lt;/a&gt;; meetups are exploding, but they don’t take the format of a traditional board meeting. They’re an accelerated version of the preceding online conversation, where smileys are replaced by actual body language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We needn’t get rid of the board meeting but we can make it a sleeker, more elegant thing. A board meetup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Bibliography:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve Blank, &lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2011/06/01/why-board-meetings-suck-%E2%80%93-part-1-of-2/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Why Board Meetings Suck – Part 1 of 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steve Blank, &lt;a href=&quot;https://steveblank.com/2011/06/02/reinventing-the-board-meeting-%E2%80%93-part-2-of-2-virtual-valley-ventures/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Reinventing the Board Meeting – Part 2 of 2 – Virtual Valley Ventures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fred Destin, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freddestin.com/blog/2010/06/saving-time-in-preparing-for-board-meetings.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Saving time in preparing for board meetings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark Suster, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bothsidesofthetable.com/2010/02/12/running-more-effective-board-meetings-at-startups/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Running More Effective Board Meetings at Startups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guy Kawasaki, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.guykawasaki.com/2006/03/the_art_of_the_.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Art of the Board Meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Death by sub-clauses, change of tense and jargon</title>
   <link href="https://example.com/death-by-sub-clauses-change-of-tense-and-jargon/"/>
   <updated>2011-03-28T11:24:56+01:00</updated>
   <id>https://example.com/death-by-sub-clauses-change-of-tense-and-jargon</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Below is a quote from a book I’m reading. If anybody can tell me wtf it means please comment below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Thus, it is altogether clear that a corporate governance framework that is not consistent with the social and economic requirement of non-listed companies will yield imperfections over time and would not achieve the legal strategies to control agency problems and reduce transaction costs.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;- McCahery &amp;amp; Vermeulen, Corporate Governance of Non-Listed Companies (OUP, 2008)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
</feed>
