<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <title>Your Title - india</title>
 <link href="https://example.com/tag/india/index.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="https://example.com/tag/india.html"/>
 <updated>2016-12-05T13:31:33+00:00</updated>
 <id>https://example.com/tag/india.html</id>
 <author>
   <name>Author Here</name>
 </author>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Post-Strauss England</title>
   <link href="https://example.com/post-strauss-england/"/>
   <updated>2012-08-20T15:13:35+01:00</updated>
   <id>https://example.com/post-strauss-england</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Assuming Andrew Strauss resigns the captaincy after the current Test and chooses not to tour this winter, my team for the first Test in Ahmedabad in November would be as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alastair Cook*&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Joe Root&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jonathan Trott&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ian Bell&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;James Taylor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jonny Bairstow&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Matt Prior†&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stuart Broad&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Graeme Swann&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;James Anderson&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Steven Finn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the rest of the first-class squad:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;James Tredwell&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Graham Onions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eoin Morgan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tim Bresnan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not 100% fit (mentally or physically) so not included: Ravi Bopara, Chris Tremlett&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlucky: Monty Panesar, Chris Woakes, Samit Patel, Nick Compton&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bit boring and predictable for me, but I think that’s a testament to the good stuff coming from Andy Flower and Geoff Miller.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Why doesn't India have the top-ranked Test team?</title>
   <link href="https://example.com/why-doesnt-india-have-the-top-ranked-test-team/"/>
   <updated>2011-08-23T12:00:35+01:00</updated>
   <id>https://example.com/why-doesnt-india-have-the-top-ranked-test-team</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;India could be the world’s #1 Test Match team if they wanted to. With unlimited money and an unlimited supply of players it would be trivial to put out a team that could beat all others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only logical conclusion is that they don’t want to have the top-ranked team. That’s not to say they want a low-ranked team, just that being top in Test Matches isn’t important to them. “Them” in this case being the Board of Control for Cricket in India (BCCI). One imagines the players themselves would quite like to be #1, and there’s no doubt many of the Indian fans would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching the last rites of this disappointing Test series at The Oval yesterday, I noticed that the Indian fans who were wearing replica kit were wearing the blue limited-overs strip. The England fans were wearing white Test Match replica kit. This may be a clue. The long form isn’t that big a deal outside England at the moment (and I include Cardiff in that sweeping statement).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BCCI could afford to dominate all forms of cricket. Currently their chosen battlegrounds are One Day Internationals and bureaucracy. They promote their own domestic Twenty20 competition over the international equivalent because they control it 100% and the revenue does not have to be shared with their acolyte countries Bangladesh and Zimbabwe. But I’m no nearer understanding why they don’t want it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it a simple RoI calculation? The fans prefer other forms of the game so the revenue from Test Matches is lower…therefore it’s not a priority? That would be breathtaking cynicism.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Not the whole story</title>
   <link href="https://example.com/not-the-whole-story/"/>
   <updated>2009-02-01T19:33:24+00:00</updated>
   <id>https://example.com/not-the-whole-story</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The International Cricket Council (ICC) has today &lt;a href=&quot;https://icc-cricket.yahoo.com/media-release/2009/February/media-release20090201-3.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;decided&lt;/a&gt; to revert the result of the 2006 Oval test match between England and Pakistan to the original one decided by the umpires: an England win due to the match being forfeited by Pakistan as a result of them failing to take the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A footnote in cricket history - the series was won by England anyway and this merely changes the series score from 2-0 to 3-0. And an outbreak of common sense since the earlier ICC ruling to award the draw to Pakistan gave losing teams the Get Out Of Jail Free option of simply refusing to take the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But little is straightforward in international cricket and there is surely more to the timing of this than meets the eye. On the same day, the ICC also announced that Pakistan would not host the 2009 Champions Trophy. Again, this was on the face of it a common sense decision based on legitimate security concerns in Pakistan. It’s the timing that smells of politics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know enough about Indian and Pakistani politics to understand what’s going on here. The interesting thing to me is that nobody seems to be commenting on this. &lt;a href=&quot;https://content-uk.cricinfo.com/ci-icc/content/current/story/388625.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cricinfo&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.bbc.co.uk/sport1/hi/cricket/7863464.stm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BBC&lt;/a&gt; are simply reporting these two stories as unrelated press releases following a routine ICC meeting. That’s surely not the case.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
</feed>
