<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <title>Your Title - ofcom</title>
 <link href="https://example.com/tag/ofcom/index.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="https://example.com/tag/ofcom.html"/>
 <updated>2016-12-05T13:31:33+00:00</updated>
 <id>https://example.com/tag/ofcom.html</id>
 <author>
   <name>Author Here</name>
 </author>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Digital Economy Act</title>
   <link href="https://example.com/the-digital-economy-act/"/>
   <updated>2010-04-15T16:42:45+01:00</updated>
   <id>https://example.com/the-digital-economy-act</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don’t climb aboard many bandwagons - there’s usually enough passengers already - but the confluence of the forthcoming UK general election and the hasty passing of the Digital Economy Act encouraged me to do some research into what was being done in our name at Westminster. I intend to use my vote and I want to do so with a bit of background knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I’m going to get on this bandwagon it will be with information from primary sources as far as possible. Received opinions are as useful as second-hand food. So at the bottom of this post is a handy list of things I’ve read. If you want the facts, stop reading now and read those documents instead. What follows is my amateur opinion: your opinion is just as valid so go form one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://interactive.bis.gov.uk/digitalbritain/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Digital Economy Act 2010&lt;/a&gt; means that your ISP can be forced by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ofcom&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;OFCOM&lt;/a&gt; to hand over details of your internet activity to the holder of intellectual property rights if a court of law thinks you have committed a breach of the copyright law. A court order is required for this - it's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opsi.gov.uk/acts/acts2010/plain/ukpga_20100024_en#Legislation-IDAMWEBB&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;in the Act&lt;/a&gt; and it's in OFCOM's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ofcom.org.uk/telecoms/copyright/tor/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Terms of Reference document&lt;/a&gt; they published in response to the Act. If your ISP hands over your details to a third party without a court order then that's a commercial decision for them, not a legal obligation. Check out your ISP's policy on this.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;If a rightsholder makes enough &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opsi.gov.uk/acts/acts2010/plain/ukpga_20100024_en#Legislation-IDAZ0EBB&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;accusations&lt;/a&gt; against you to reach an OFCOM-determined threshold then OFCOM can oblige your ISP to take &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opsi.gov.uk/acts/acts2010/plain/ukpga_20100024_en#p00110&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;technical measures&lt;/a&gt;&quot; against you. These measures include disconnection or any other limiting of your service. OFCOM must believe these measures will be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opsi.gov.uk/acts/acts2010/plain/ukpga_20100024_en#Legislation-IDAMOMTF&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;effective&lt;/a&gt; before it can impose the obligation on the ISP, which presupposes that OFCOM believes there is merit in the accusations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it’s all down to OFCOM. The law gives it the opportunity to act in the interests of the rightsholders, the service providers or the subscribers. Or all three if it gets its policies dead right. It will conduct itself in accordance with a code yet to be drafted. It could draft such a code itself or it could adopt one proposed by somebody else, including copyright holders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The draft code will be published by May. Popular activity (albeit sometimes hysterical) has made sure that some bad amendments were dropped during the debate on the Bill. Legislators are aware that the internet community is vociferous and includes some influential people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a good chance the draft code will be OK, but &lt;strong&gt;the price of liberty is eternal vigilance&lt;/strong&gt;. OFCOM promises to engage with consumer groups as part of the consultation process before the code is submitted to the European Commission for approval - how effective that is depends on continued pressure from actual internet users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bibliography&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opsi.gov.uk/acts/acts2010/plain/ukpga_20100024_en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Digital Economy Act 2010&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ofcom.org.uk/telecoms/copyright/tor/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;OFCOM Measures to Tackle Online Copyright Infringement: Terms of Reference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://digitaleconomyact.info&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Digital Economy Act wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_Economy_Act_2010&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wikipedia article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bpi.co.uk/press-area/news-amp3b-press-release/article/bpi-heralds-landmark-digital-economy-act.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;BPI Heralds Landmark Digital Economy Act&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;BIS official guidelines: &lt;a href=&quot;https://interactive.bis.gov.uk/digitalbritain/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/Example-infringement-notifications.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Online infringement of copyright: libraries, universities and wi-fi providers (PDF)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://services.parliament.uk/hansard/Commons/bydate/20100406/mainchamberdebates/part005.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hansard&lt;/a&gt; record of the Commons Second Reading of the Digital Economy Bill&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
</feed>
